BEN SLINDE

Buford, GA 30519

Phone: 678.926.8686 | Email: benjaminslinde@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/benjamin-slinde GitHub: https://github.com/stevenslade Portfolio: https://github.com/stevenslade/Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the Georgia Institute of Technology. Also have a degree in Mechanical Engineering and 17 years experience in a manufacturing environment, deploying new products and processes. Experienced in global technology acquisition and process deployment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL

Applications: GitHub, Heroku

Tools: Microsoft Office, Agile Methodology

PROJECTS

Book Club Collective | https://github.com/stevenslade/Book-Club-Collective | https://intense-tor-64466.herokuapp.com/

- BCC allows a user to make a profile, search for books using Google Books API, write reviews which are stored to the BCC database. Reviews are averaged for a BCC review rating. Users can also make reading clubs for the purpose of meeting other readers.
- Role: Full Stack, APIs to Google Books, Javascript, Handlebars
- Skill Usage: MVC paradigm, API, Handlebars, mySQL, star rating is

Hiking Hub | https://github.com/stevenslade/Hiking-Hub | https://stevenslade.github.io/Hiking-Hub/

- Hiking Hub allows a user to enter a city, it then returns local hiking options. Once the user selects a hiking location, the app then returns reddit listings for the selection.
- Role: Back-end team, APIs to Reddit, Google Maps, generating HTML
- Skill Usage: HTML, Tailwind CSS, User Input, local storage, multiple API fetch

Weather Forecast | https://github.com/stevenslade/WeatherDashboard | https://stevenslade.github.io/WeatherDashboard/

- This app allows the user to enter a city, it then provides the current weather and a five day forecast. The app stores historical searches in local memory and provides a button for one click searches.
- Role: Sole Author
- Skill Usage: HTML, Bootstrap CSS, User Input, local storage, API fetch

EXPERIENCE

At Home Parent

2016 - Present

• Managed Slinde Household

Process Development Engineering Manager Freudenberg-NOK

2014 - 2016 Cleveland, GA

Managed department of engineers, technicians and students whose responsibilities included process development, machine deployment and process support.

- Wrote machine specifications for new equipment.
- Purchased equipment globally and deployed equipment in global operations.
- Managed team of five engineers.
- Assigned and prioritized technicians according to production requirements.
- Mentored students in process engineering and six sigma and lean systems methods primarily focused on scrap reduction.

Engineering Supervisor Freudenberg-NOK

2013 – 2014 Cleveland, GA

Responsible for all metrics of after molding machine operations and deployment of new after molding operations.

- Improved after molding OEE from 70% to 85% in three months, to 92% in six.
- Directed daily activities of four technicians across three shifts.
- Interfaced directly with customers regarding non-conforming product concerns.
- Generated all documentation for new product and process launches including PFEMA, Process Flow, Work Instructions.

Senior Manufacturing Engineer Freudenberg-NOK

2007 - 2013 Cleveland, GA

Managed product and process launches, equipment and product transfers, and supported current production with process improvement activities.

- Transfer product operation running in Cuautla at 30% scrap to Cleveland, running at 3% scrap in four months.
- Deploy new molding and after molding equipment.
- Work Continuously to reduce scrap in production operations.
- Engage with customers to resolve non-conorming product issues.

Senior Production Engineer Toyota Denso

2005 - 2007

Pendergrass, GA

Started-up a new compressor plant in Pendergrass, Georgia.

- Plant start-up experience.
- Directed department activities during the Engineering Manager's deployment.
- Focused on process improvement activities including reducing short period stops (SPS), quality improvements and tool life extensions.
- Generated all documentation for new process launch, including PFMEAs, Process Flow, Control Plans, Work Instructions.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: Georgia Tech, Atlanta, GA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering: Youngstown State University, Youngstown, OH GPA 3.89/4.0, Graduated Summa Cum Laude